pec.org.pk 2019-08-04

# 

**Privacy Policy**

We are committed to protecting your personal information and your right to privacy. If you have any questions or concerns about our policy, or our practices with regards to your personal information, please email on privacy@pec.org.pk.

This Privacy Policy governs the privacy policies and practices of our website and online solutions. Please read our Privacy Policy carefully as it will help you make informed decisions about sharing your personal information with us.

We last updated our Privacy Policy on 30th May 2019.

  1. **Information We Collect**

As a Visitor, you can browse our website & online solutions to find out more Pakistan Engineering Council. You are not required to provide us with any personal information as a Visitor.

We collect your personal information when you register with us either as engineer, constructor, operator, or consultant firm. We may gather your personal information, when you apply for accreditation of any engineering batch. The personal information is collected when you register any complaint on PEC complaint management system.

The personal information that we collect depends on the context of your interaction with us and the online solutions, the choices you make and the solutions you use. The personal information we collect can include the following:

  1. Name, CNIC, email, contact data and academic data.

  2. Payment Information: If you choose to register for license of any type from PEC, we collect payment information proof. All payment information is securely stored by our payment processor and we do not require access to your sensitive information, such as credit card number or security code.

  3. Business Information: we may ask specific information related to engineering experience business in order to complete the business process.

  2. **Automatically Collected Information**

When you use our website, we automatically collect certain computer information by the interaction of your mobile phone or web browser with our website. Such information is typically considered non-personal information. We also collect the following:

  1. Cookies

Our website uses "Cookies" to identify the areas of our website that you have visited. A Cookie is a small piece of data stored on your computer or mobile device by your web browser. We use Cookies to personalize the Content that you see on our website. Most web browsers can be set to disable the use of Cookies. However, if you disable Cookies, you may not be able to access functionality on our website correctly or at all. We never place Personally Identifiable Information in Cookies.

  2. Third Party Tools

We also use third party tools to improve the performance and features of our website. These third party tracking tools are designed to collect only non-personal information about your use of our website. However, you understand that such tools are created and managed by parties outside our control. As such, we are not responsible for what information is actually captured by such third parties or how such third parties use and protect that information.

  3. Log Information

We automatically receive information from your web browser or mobile device. This information includes the name of the website from which you entered our website, if any, as well as the name of the website to which you're headed when you leave our website. This information also includes the IP address of your computer/proxy server that you use to access the Internet, your Internet website provider name, web browser type, type of mobile device, and computer operating system. We use all of this information to analyze trends among our Users to help improve our website.

  3. **How and Why We Use Your Personal Information**

We use the information we receive from you as follows:

  1. To customize our website & online solutions for your experience.

We may use the information you provide to us along with any computer information we receive to customize our website.

  2. For data aggregation purposes

We retain the right to collect and use any non-personal information collected from your use of our website and aggregate such data for internal analytics that improve our website and Services. At no time is your personally identifiable information included in such data aggregations.

  4. **Transfer of Personal Information**

Your information, including personal information, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your province, country or governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your personal information will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

  5. **Disclosure of Personal & business Information**

Under certain circumstances, we may be required to disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency) or legal forums covered under PEC Act.

If you are member engineer, we will expose your name, membership detail, domicile information, masked CNIC and graduation detail on verification.pec.org.pk

If you are a registered firm as Constructor, Operator or Consultant, we will expose brief profile of your business firm for public verification on verificatgion.pec.org.pk. Under brief profile, License, contact, owners, employed engineers and specialized codes information of the firm is exposed.

  6. **Direct marketing**

PEC will only engage in direct marketing in accordance with applicable laws. Where relevant, we may send you direct marketing communications and information about our services and offerings that we consider may be of interest to you.

These communications may be sent in various forms, including mail, SMS and email. If you indicate a preference for a method of communication, we will endeavor to use that method whenever practical to do so. 

  7. **Retention of Your Personal Information**

We will retain your personal information only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in PEC Act, Byelaws and notifications/SROs issued over time. We will retain and use your information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

  8. **Service Providers**

We employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our website & online solutions ("Service Providers"), to provide our solutions on our behalf, to perform solution-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our website or any solutions is used. These third-parties have access to your personal information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

  9. **Analytics**

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/

  10. **Links to Third-Party websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites that are not under our direct control. These websites may have their own policies regarding privacy. We have no control of or responsibility for linked websites and provide these links solely for the convenience and information of our visitors. You access such linked websites at your own risk. These websites are not subject to this Privacy Policy. You should check the privacy policies, if any, of those individual websites to see how the operators of those third-party websites will utilize your personal information. In addition, these websites may contain a link to websites of our affiliates. The websites of our affiliates are not subject to this Privacy Policy, and you should check their individual privacy policies to see how the operators of such websites will utilize your personal information.

  11. **Updates to Our Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify on our website, by a blog post, by email, or by any method we determine. The method we chose is at our sole discretion. We will also change the "Last Updated" date at the beginning of this Privacy Policy. Any changes we make to our Privacy Policy are effective as of this Last Updated date and replace any prior Privacy Policies.

  12. **Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this policy, please contact us at privacy@pec.org.pk.
